Haverhill, Mass. First Congregational Church records, 1719-2012.
Congregational Library Archives
- First Congregational Church records, 1900 2011; 1900-2011; 197 Files; (14 volumes, 172 folders, 9 tapes)
  - Church and membership records, 1939 2011; 1939-2011; 72 Files; (6 volumes, 64 folders)
    - Pastoral Search Committee pamphlet, 1978 (Box 9, Folder 35)
      This pamphlet was originally filed with the North Parish Community Church records.
    - Church register, 1980 2003; 1980-2003 (Box 7, Volume 3)
    - Church surveys and evaluations, 1982 2002; 1982-2002 (Box 8, Folder 19)
    - Funeral services and memorials, 1987 2005; 1987-2005 (Box 5, Folder 23)
    - Church policy, 1988, undated (Box 5, Folder 24)
    - List of marriages performed by Rev. Frank Graichen, 1991 (Box 5, Folder 25)
    - Confirmations, 1991 2003; 1991-2003 (Box 5, Folder 26)
    - 135th anniversary celebration, 1994 (Box 8, Folder 20)
    - Miscellaneous membership records, 1996 2004; 1996-2004 (Box 6, Folder 19)
      This folder appears to have been used for unsorted membership records of all types. This folder contains examples of baptismal records, membership transfers, reception letters, marriage records, and obituary records.
    - Robert Coppola moderator records, 1997 1999; 1997-1999 (Box 6, Folder 20)
    - Church register, 1997 2009; 1997-2009 (Box 7, Volume 4)
    - Membership database printout, 2000 2001; 2000-2001 (Box 6, Folder 21)
    - Website documentation and records, 2003 2006; 2003-2006 (Box 8, Folder 21)
    - Disbursement of building sale funds, 2008 2009; 2008-2009 (Box 8, Folder 22)
    - Donation of artifacts to the Peabody Essex Museum, 2009 2010; 2009-2010 (Box 8, Folder 23)
    - Membership cards, 1900 1999; circa twentieth-century (Box 11)
  - Newsletters, 1946 2011; 1946-2011; 33 Files; (2 volumes, 31 folders)
    This sub-series contains extensive copies of near weekly newsletters and orders of worship produced by the First Congregational Church. These newsletters are not complete as occasional single issues and some major gaps exist. However, overall, it is a fascinatingly thorough accounting of the weekly activities of the church and church community.
    - The Church Clock, 1946 1949; 1946-1949 (Box 7, Volume 7)
    - The Church Clock, 1949 1951; 1949-1951 (Box 7, Volume 8)
    - First Church Messenger, 1953 1954; 1953-1954 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - First Church Messenger, 1955 1956; 1955-1956 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - First Church Messenger, 1957 1958; 1957-1958 (Box 3, Folder 25)
    - The Church Family, 1960 1961; 1960-1961 (Box 7, Folder 4)
    - The Church Family, 1962 1963; 1962-1963 (Box 7, Folder 5)
    - The Church Family, 1964 1965; 1964-1965 (Box 7, Folder 6)
    - The Church Family, 1966 1968; 1966-1968 (Box 7, Folder 7)
    - The Church Family, 1970 1973; 1970-1973 (Box 7, Folder 8)
    - The Church Family, 1974 1975; 1974-1975 (Box 3, Folder 26)
    - The Church Family, 1976 1978; 1976-1978 (Box 7, Folder 9)
    - The Church Family, 1979 1980; 1979-1980 (Box 7, Folder 10)
    - The Church Family, 1980 1981; 1980-1981 (Box 3, Folder 27)
    - The Church Family, 1982 1983; 1982-1983 (Box 3, Folder 28)
    - The Church Family, 1984 1985; 1984-1985 (Box 3, Folder 29)
    - The Church Family, 1986 (Box 3, Folder 30)
    - The Church Family, 1987 1988; 1987-1988 (Box 7, Folder 11)
    - The Church Family, 1989 1990; 1989-1990 (Box 7, Folder 12)
    - The Church Family, 1991 1992; 1991-1992 (Box 7, Folder 13)
    - The Church Family, 1993 1994; 1993-1994 (Box 7, Folder 14)
    - The Church Family, 1995 1996; 1995-1996 (Box 7, Folder 15)
    - The Church Family, 1997 1998; 1997-1998 (Box 7, Folder 16)
    - The Church Family, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 17)
    - The Church Family, 2000 (Box 8, Folder 1)
    - The Church Family, 2002 (Box 8, Folder 2)
    - The Church Family, 2005 (Box 8, Folder 3)
    - The Church Family, 2006 (Box 8, Folder 4)
    - The Church Family, 2007 (Box 8, Folder 5)
    - The Church Family, 2008 (Box 8, Folder 6)
    - The Church Family, 2009 (Box 8, Folder 7)
    - The Church Family, 2010 2011; 2010-2011 (Box 8, Folder 8)
    - The Pastor's Perch, 1987 1988; 1987-1988 (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Financial and building records, 1947 2009; 1947-2009; 21 Folders
    This sub-series contains both financial records and records related to the operation and maintenance of the physical church building. Included within this sub series are treasurer and financial committee reports, architectural drawings, audits, records of bequests, and reports on the church's Tiffany windows.
    - Mary M. Tibbetts educational fund, 1947 2001; 1947-2001 (Box 6, Folder 22)
    - Architectural drawings, 1956 1987; 1956, 1987 (Folder 8)
    - Chapel gifts and memorials, 1962 (Box 3, Folder 17)
    - Building records, 1963 1975; 1963-1975 (Box 6, Folder 23)
    - Memorial fund, 1967 1990; 1967-1990 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Treasurer's reports, 1972 1974; 1972-1974 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Building records, 1981 1998; 1981-1998 (Box 6, Folder 24)
    - Stained glass Tiffany windows, 1975 1997; 1975-1997 (Box 6, Folder 25)
    - Finance committee records, 1982 1987; 1982-1987 (Box 6, Folder 26)
    - Finance committee records, 1989 (Box 6, Folder 27)
    - Finance committee records, 1991 1994; 1991-1994 (Box 6, Folder 28)
    - Finance committee records, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 29)
    - Finance committee records, 1988 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Finance committee records, 1999 2001; 1999-2001 (Box 6, Folder 30)
    - Finance committee records, 2001 2004; 2001-2004 (Box 6, Folder 31)
    - Bequests, 1992 1997; 1992, 1997 (Box 6, Folder 32)
    - Capital repairs, 1994 2003; 1994-2003 (Box 6, Folder 33)
    - Building renovations, 1998 (Box 6, Folder 34)
    - Financial records, 2005 (Box 6, Folder 35)
    - Financial audit, 2009 (Box 6, Folder 36)
    - Land diagrams, undated (Box 3, Folder 21)
  - Sermons, 1959 2000; 1959-2000; 4 Folders
    This sub-series contains manuscript sermons preached by ministers at the First Congregational Church.
    - Dewey Peterson sermons, 1959 1961; 1959-1961 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - 135th anniversary sermon, 1994 (Box 7, Folder 1)
    - Harvey Joyner sermons, 1999 (Box 7, Folder 2)
    - Lois Coppola sermons, 2000 (Box 7, Folder 3)
- North Parish Community Church records, 1924 1970; 1924-1970; 14 Folders
  This series contains the records of the North Parish Community Church in Haverhill, Massachusetts, and contains administrative records, financial records, membership records, and records related to the merger between the North Parish and the First Congregational Church.
  - Membership lists, 1924 1957; 1924-1957 (Box 9, Folder 21)
  - North Parish meeting warrants, 1925 1954; 1925-1954 (Box 9, Folder 22)
  - North Parish annual reports, 1928 1963; 1928-1963 (Box 9, Folder 23)
  - Financial records, 1927-1936 (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Financial records, 1937-1964 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Church records, 1929 1963; 1929-1963 (Box 9, Folder 24)
  - Membership records, 1934 1947; 1934-1947 (Box 9, Folder 25)
  - Membership records, 1950 1957; 1950-1957 (Box 9, Folder 26)
  - Congregational Christian Churches yearbook reports, 1952 1955; 1952-1955 (Box 9, Folder 27)
  - Church records, 1957 1961; 1957-1961 (Box 9, Folder 28)
  - Council meeting minutes, 1959 1960; 1959-1960 (Box 9, Folder 29)
  - North Parish church study, 1962 (Box 9, Folder 30)
  - Merger Steering Committee records, 1963 1970; 1963-1970 (Box 9, Folder 31)
  - By-laws, undated (Box 9, Folder 32)